紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   肉松
翻譯   鹽湖涼開水
翻譯   蘇小黛
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯   沫沫
翻譯   Lynn_寧
時間軸   紙袋P
時間軸  王者蔥
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對   草草
總監   草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第十三集
生日快樂
尊敬的國務卿女士
我謹辭去合眾國總統職務
此致  弗蘭西斯·J·安德伍德
羅梅洛議員呼吁在總統辭職后解散司法委員會
道格·斯坦普
抗議者在白宮草坪被擊斃
弗蘭西斯
你覺得那是誰
Who does that look like to you?
一個等列車的普通白人
Just another white guy waiting for the train.
-給  拿上這個  -不行
- Here, take this. - No.
拿著
Come on.
你知道總統怎么想嗎
Do you know what the president thinks?
他覺得你是泄密者
He thinks you're the leak.
那倒好了
I wish.
我們需要你讓自己跟佐伊·巴恩斯的死掛上鉤
We need you to implicate yourself in the death of Zoe Barnes.
我失陪一下好嗎
Can you excuse me?
還是你覺得我不夠投入
You don't think that I'm dedicated enough?
太投入了
Too dedicated.
我殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
I killed Zoe Barnes.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
我認為道格·斯坦普殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
I believe Doug Stamper killed Zoe Barnes.
為了弗蘭西斯·安德伍德殺了她
And killed her to benefit Francis Underwood.
一共六個人
There were six of them,
他們輪流來
and they all took a turn.
除了羅梅洛
Except for Romero.
但我知道真相
But I know the real story.
她叫羅謝爾
Her name was, uh, Rochelle.
救命  救命
Help. Help.
湯姆
Tom.
我需要你的服務
I need your services.
我要向委員會和全國人民宣布
I am announcing to this committee and to the nation
明晚6點起
that as of 6:00 p.m. tomorrow evening,
我將辭去美國總統一職
I shall resign the office of President of the United States.
羅梅洛議員
Oh, Congressman Romero,
我只是想走前最后看你一眼
I just wanted to see you one last time before I leave.
我覺得沒什么好說的了
I don't believe there's anything left to be said.
我倆確實無話可說了
No, not between us. Not any longer.
我只是想謝謝
I just wanted to thank you for...
你的韌勁
your tenacity.
無論你想干什么  你都無法逍遙法外
Whatever you're up to, you won't get away with it.
也許我已經做到了
Maybe I already have.
委員會將繼續工作
The committee will continue its work.
我們會建議司法部提出起訴
We'll recommend charges to DOJ.
羅謝爾
Rochelle.
多美的名字
Such a lovely name.
告訴我你有多么不想那名字上新聞
Tell me how much you don't want that to end up in the press.
然后解散這個委員會
And then shut this committee down.
你得無條件聽我的
No deals.
總統先生  總統先生
Mr. President! Mr. President!
你怎么能這樣
How could you?
-你怎么能不提前告訴我  -為了保護你
- How could you not warn me? - To protect you.
-我是要保護你  -你別碰我
- I was protecting you. - You should take your hands off me.
如果你覺得措手不及  我理解
No, look, I understand if you feel broadsided.
-我不在意什么感覺  弗蘭西斯  -但聽我說
- I don't care about feelings, Francis. - But listen to me...
克萊爾  聽我說
Look, Claire, listen to me.
你讓我把丑出盡了
You made me look absolutely ridiculous.
-毫無準備  稀里糊涂  -不  克萊爾
- Ill-prepared and ignorant. - No! Claire.
-我們有一條規則  弗蘭西斯  -不
- We have one rule, Francis. - No,
-一條  -現在沒了
- One rule.  - not anymore. Not anymore.
-沒了  -如果我不知道你的想法
- We don't. - I cannot be your ally
就無法當你的盟友
if I don't know what you're thinking.
克萊爾  事情本會鬧個沒完
Listen, Claire. It would have never ended.
好吧  就算阻止了司法委員會
All right, fine, we got to stop judiciary,
其他委員會也會冒出來
but other committees would have sprung up,
一直指控我們
just to keep the charges going.
監管  軍事  外事  情報等等委員會
Oversight, Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, Intelligence.
事情會沒完沒了的
It would have gone on and on.
-年復一年的  -我不管  弗蘭西斯
- Years and - I don't care, Francis.
-調查  -你該跟我說的
- years of investigation. - You should have talked to me,
而不是像這樣臨時決定
instead of making a last-minute decision like this.
我沒有
I didn't.
我制造了這混亂  好利用它
I created this confusion in order to take advantage of it.
所有事情都是計劃好的
Everything that has happened... was planned.
何時開始的
Since when?
去極樂之地前
Since before Elysian Fields.
但我是在極樂之地猛然領悟到
But it was at Elysian Fields that it hit me.
我明白了
I saw it...
就像頭頂上的燈泡亮了起來
almost like a light bulb going off above my head.
真正的權力在何處
Where does the real power lie?
就是權力背后的權力
The power behind the power.
克萊爾  我明白了
And I understood, Claire,
我們不能像過去那樣思考行動
that we have to think and act differently than we ever have.
因為關鍵已經不在于誰住在白宮
Because it's no longer about who lives in the White House...
而在于誰擁有白宮
it's about who owns the White House.
這可是總統一職  政客還能爬多高
This is the presidency. How much higher can a politician go?
真正的權力不在這兒
The real power isn't here.
而在之外
It's beyond here.
超越了它  但仍要與之配合工作
It's above it, but still working in conjunction with it.
克萊爾  你我一直都在圈內
Look, Claire, you and I have always been on the inside.
被困在泡泡里
Trapped. In the bubble.
但從今往后
But going forward...
我在私營部門經營圈外
with my operating on the outside, in the private sector,
你在這里工作
and you working from here...
我們能一起擁有白宮
we can own this house together.
你不明白嗎  這是我計劃好的
Don't you see? I've designed this.
我想讓你當總統
I wanted you to be the president.
我讓你成為了總統
I've made you the president.
我該向你道謝嗎
Am I supposed to say thank you?
不
No.
但你得赦免我  赦免我所有的罪行
But you will have to pardon me. Pardon me for all of my crimes.
作為總統  只有你才能這么做
As the president, you're the only one who can.
弗蘭西斯  如果我這么做會被彈劾
Francis, I could be impeached if I do that.
不會的  戴維斯和厄舍
No, no. Look, Davis and Usher,
他們可以保護你
they're in a position to protect you.
-他們希望你成功  -世事難料  弗蘭西斯
- They want you to succeed. - We can be sure of nothing, Francis.
道格的事
Everything going on with Doug,
白宮還有泄密者
the leak still in the White House...
不  那也是我
No, that was me, too.
-什么  -我就是泄密者
- What? - I'm the leak.
這幾個月我一直在道格的幫助下
I've been feeding information to Tom Hammerschmidt
給湯姆·漢默施密特放料
for months with Doug's help.
這沒道理  弗蘭西斯
That doesn't make any sense, Francis.
克萊爾  如果你在別人之前扳倒自己
Claire, when you bring yourself down before someone else can,
你就能控制這個過程了
you control the way it happens.
只有這條路才能讓我們來到此刻
This was the only path to get us to this moment
你和我  能夠擁有一切
where you and I can own it all.
撤掉監控
Get rid of the surveillance.
抹除一切  停掉一切  你跟道格做的一切
Erase it. Shut everything down. Anything you and Doug were up to.
好  但是你得先赦免我
All right. But you have to pardon me first.
等時機合適  還要赦免道格
And, at the right time, Doug.
否則我們可能都要進監獄
Or we could both go to prison.
我殺了湯姆
I killed Tom.
我殺了湯姆·耶茨  他死了
I killed Tom Yates. He's dead.
我讓馬克處理掉了
And I had Mark clean it up.
所以這永遠不會追查到我們
So it will never make its way back to us.
那我們都做了必須做的事
Well, then I guess we both did what we had to.
-你知道他要做這事嗎  -不知道
- Did you know he was gonna do this? - No.
因為這很不好  克萊爾  這非常不好
Because this is bad, Claire. This is very... very bad.
天哪
My God!
你們兩個怎么回事
What is it with you two?
-如果你在想什么  說...  -在我家里
- If there's something on your mind, say... - In my house?
你把他留在我家里了
You left him in my house?!
小聲點  至少改變你的語氣
Lower your voice, or at least change your tone.
你處理好了嗎
Did you take care of it?
是的  那是我的工作
Yes, that's what I do.
那謝謝你  做得好
Then thank you, and well done.
現在我們回到眼前的事
Now let's get back to what's in front of us.
他想讓你待在這里嗎  克萊爾
Does he even want you to be here, Claire?
馬克  拜托  我現在需要的是你的政治盤算
Mark, please. What I need right now is your political calculus.
他將你和我們所有人置于了為難的境地
He has put you, he has put all of us, in an impossible position.
你明白嗎
You see that?
如果你不能正確處理這件事  就無法恢復了
If you don't handle this correctly, you do not recover from it.
這事關政府的持續運作
This is about continuity of government.
通知北約  通知各國領導人
Informing NATO, informing world leaders.
我們本該讓大使們待命的
We should have had ambassadors on call.
參謀長聯席會議  國家安全...
Joint Chiefs of Staff, the National Security...
連尼克松都那樣做了
Even Nixon did that!
我準備好上交了
I'm ready to hand it over,
但是我要得到保證  不管怎樣
but I want to be assured that no matter what,
麥卡倫之死不會牽連到我
Macallan's death is not related to me.
這可以辦到
That can be taken care of.
-我要你手上我的東西  -好
- I want what you have of mine. - Okay.
會給你的
That's what you'll get.
我還要當幕僚長
And I want to be Chief of Staff.
我覺得這不是問題
Well, I don't think that's a problem.
很高興你在提要求
I'm glad you're asking for what you want.
道格·斯坦普會為總統做任何事
Doug Stamper would do anything for the president.
他看到了佐伊·巴恩斯的威脅
He saw a threat in Zoe Barnes,
她跟總統有私情
who the president was involved with.
他就處理掉了
And he took care of it.
他不止一次地威脅過我的生命
He's threatened my life on numerous occasions.
-但是回到我的問題  -不  女士
- But to go back to my question... - No, ma'am.
我不認為總統知道道格在做什么
I don't think the president knew what Doug was up to.
完全不了解
Not at all.
漢默施密特先生
Mr. Hammerschmidt.
我想給你打電話來著
I've been meaning to call you.
肖恩
Sean.
你應該能看出來  我現在在這里工作
As you can tell, I work here now.
我現在跟你握手
I'm shaking your hand right now
是因為我崇尚社交禮儀
because I believe in social graces.
你迷失了
You're lost.
-我不這么認為  -不  你就是迷失了
- I don't think so. - No, you are.
不  我一點都沒迷失
No, not at all.
這就是你想要的
This is what you wanted?
為腐敗的政府和走向毀滅的總統賣命
A job in a corrupt administration? Presidency in ruin?
我是在白宮里面
I'm in the White House.
不是在外面  好奇著里面是什么樣
Not out there, wondering what it's like in here.
不會很久的
Not for long.
你一旦進來了  就是進來了  這就是美國特色
Once you're in, you're in. It's the American way.
-斯坦普先生現在可以見你了  -謝謝
- Mr. Stamper will see you now. - Thank you.
抱歉讓你久等了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
當我提出這次會面時  我不知道
When I asked for this meeting, I had no idea
總統今晚要簽字辭職
the president would be signing his resignation this evening.
還有我  今天早上辭職
And I, this morning.
-我聽說了傳聞  -現在確定了
- I heard a rumor you might. - Now it's confirmed.
斯坦普先生
Mr. Stamper...
請說  你可以叫我道格
Yeah, please. You can call me Doug.
還是免了  畢竟這是正式采訪
I'd rather not, for the sake of this interview.
希望你知道這不是私下談話
I want you to know this will not be off the record,
或作為幕后消息
or on background.
我確實認識麗薩·威廉姆斯  幾年前認識的
I do know Lisa Williams. I met her a couple years ago.
好的
Okay.
但在我們談其他事之前
But before we get to anything else...
安德伍德總統
did President Underwood,
在還是議員時  是否殺害了佐伊·巴恩斯
when he was congressman, kill Zoe Barnes?
沒有
No.
斯坦普先生
Mr. Stamper...
你是否殺害了佐伊·巴恩斯
did you kill Zoe Barnes?
我沒準備好回答那個問題
I'm not prepared to answer that question.
你明白我可以白紙黑字寫明你拒絕回答吧
You understand I can use your refusal in print.
明白
Yes.
佐伊死的那天  你是否在大教堂高地
Were you on the Cathedral Heights D.C. Metro platform
地鐵站的站臺上
the day of Zoe's death?
任何涉及佐伊·巴恩斯的問題
Any questions regarding Zoe Barnes,
你得去跟我的律師談
you need to speak with my attorneys.
佐伊·巴恩斯是否用一部一次性手機
Did Zoe Barnes make a call to Francis Underwood
打給了時任議員的弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
from a burner phone when he was congressman?
-你為什么要問我  -你為什么不回答
- Why would you ask me that? - Why won't you answer?
總統的手機幾乎都是我在接
I almost always answer the president's phone.
電話  短信
Calls, texts...
你知道那些短信嗎
Do you have any knowledge of those texts?
我沒準備好作出評論
I'm not prepared to comment on that.
那么這次談話到此為止
Then this conversation is over.
祝好
Have a good day.
最后一件事
One last thing.
你是否給我寄過兩張生日賀卡
Did you send me two birthday cards?
沒有
No.
[蘇格蘭蓋爾語]
Slàinte mhath.
是蘇格蘭蓋爾語  意思是"祝安康"
That's Scottish Gaelic. It means "Good health."
我父親有點執迷
My father's kind of obsessed.
他將我們格雷森家的歷史
And he traced our line of Graysons back to,
追溯到了16世紀左右
like, 16th century or something.
如果我們午休時需要喝一杯
Well, if we ever needed a drink in the middle of the day...
聯邦檢察官那邊進展順利
It went well with the US attorney.
真令人悲痛
It's tragic.
一想到道格做了什么  我們的心都碎了
Our hearts are just broken at the thought of what Doug did.
我不知道他怎么了
I don't know what happened to him.
可能到了某個時候...
I guess somewhere along the line...
他什么時候會宣布辭職
When will, uh, he be announcing his resignation?
-今天下午  -當然
- It's happening this afternoon. - Oh, of course.
賽斯  你也得辭職
And, Seth, you'll need to resign as well.
-我還以為  -我知道  但你想想
- I thought that, uh... - I know, but think about this.
我得建立我自己的團隊  得公開進行
I need to establish my own team. Publicly.
不能回避
And there's no avoiding
目前你跟道格和弗蘭西斯的關系有多緊密
how tied you and Doug are to Francis at this point.
這只是為了等一切煙消云散  僅此而已
So, it's really just waiting for the dust to settle. That's all.
怎么感覺像是你在告訴我
Why does it feel like you're telling me
我的職業生涯結束了  副總統女士
my career is over, Madam Vice President?
不  我只是說  你得先離開一陣子
No, I'm just saying, you just need to go away for a little while.
稍后我們會召你回來的
And we'll bring you back into the fold at a later date,
不用擔心
and don't worry.
看看莉安  她也離開過  現在她回來了
Look at LeAnn. She left and now she's back.
我們以前一起喝過酒嗎
Have we ever had a drink together?
從來沒有
Never.
我想在您還是總統時  把這個交給您
I wanted to hand this to you while you were still president.
我帶著沉重的心情接受了
I accept this with a heavy heart.
我昨天跟律師們開了一個戰略會議
I had a strategy session with the attorneys yesterday.
希望他們好好對你了
I hope they're treating you well.
你知道
You know...
道格  現在起
Doug, we're not gonna be able
我們將有一陣子不能見面了
to see each other for some time now.
不如你拿點什么東西當紀念吧
So why don't you take something?
-不了  -沒關系  隨意挑吧
- No. - No, no. Go on. Take something.
任何東西  你想要什么都行  即便很小
Anything. Anything you want. Even if it's small.
一個你能握在手里
Something you can hold in your hand
讓你回想起這里的東西  直到你回來
to remind you of this place... until you get back.
隨便選吧
You go on.
離我的正式辭職只有幾小時了
We're a few hours away from my official resignation...
而你還沒答應赦免我
and you still have not agreed to pardon me.
如果你不
And if you don't,
我將不得不撤回辭職的決定
I will be forced to renege on that resignation.
那就太過分了
That would be outrageous.
我遞交了簽字辭呈  才算正式辭職
Well, it isn't official until I submit a signed letter.
這對你余下的總統任期有什么好處
And what would that do to the rest of your presidency?
還能剩下什么
What would be left of it?
克萊爾  如果你不同意
Claire, if you don't do it,
你可能就要與重罪犯是夫妻了
you're gonna risk being married to a felon.
如果我同意  那又置我于何地
And if I do, where does that leave me?
你現在真的想和我談這個嗎
Look, is this really the conversation you want to be having?
你給我設局  弗蘭西斯
You've trapped me, Francis.
不  我不接受害了你的指責
No, I do not accept that I've done something to you.
我給你提供了一個機會
I have provided you with an opportunity.
你之前也說過  這就是你的終局
Now, you have said before, that this is your endgame.
眼下你的終極目標唾手可得
And now, your goal is within spitting distance
而你只看到了背叛  我不信
and all you see is betrayal? I don't buy it.
別再糾結我對你做了什么了
Stop talking about what I've done to you.
承認吧
Admit it.
這就是你想要的
This is what you want.
你愿意為之殺人
You were willing to kill for it.
那么克萊爾  接受吧
So, Claire, come and take it...
不然我就要收回了
before I take it back.
我們要挑選最合適的時機和地點
We'll find the most strategic time and place.
但我會特赦你  弗蘭西斯
But I will pardon you, Francis.
為了國家利益  我們也應該解散委員會
For the good of the nation, we need to disband this committee,
把這一頁翻過去
and put this behind us.
總統很可能撐不過聽證會
The president most likely would not have survived the hearings.
你也可以說他是被迫辭職
You could argue that he had no choice but to resign.
但我們也不能否認他的證詞引起很大反響
But we can't deny that his testimony struck a chord.
就算是這樣
Well, that may be true.
那你  羅梅洛議員
But how is it that you, Congressman Romero,
他最主要的批評者  怎么轉而支持他了呢
his biggest critic, are supporting him now?
歷史
History.
今天結束時
By the end of the day,
我們國家會第一次有位女總統
the country will have its first woman president.
我一直支持有一位女性
Look, I've always been a supporter of the idea
能入主白宮
of a woman in the Oval Office.
但是說到底
But when all is said and done,
您應該清楚弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
you do realize that Francis Underwood
今晚還是會在白宮過夜的吧
will still be sleeping in the White House tonight?
你不是該收拾東西了嗎
Isn't this when you pack everything up?
至少帶走個人物品
Or at least take the personal things?
我什么都不拿了
I'm not taking anything.
任你處置吧
You can do what you want with it.
-你什么時候見聯邦檢察官  -后天
- When do you meet with the US attorney? - Day after tomorrow.
我從沒想過弗蘭克·安德伍德會下臺
I never thought that Frank Underwood would not be president.
真沒想過
Not really.
你可以逃跑
You could just run away.
那我有什么好處
What does that get me?
你很擅長照顧自己
You're good at taking care of yourself.
真好笑
That's funny.
我希望你知道我關心你
Look, I want you to know that I care for you,
但恐怕我也幫不上你什么了
but I don't know how much I can be there.
我想就在這里坐一會兒
I think I'm gonna just sit here for a while.
嗯  坐吧
Yeah, you should.
副總統希望你在她宣誓就職之前
Uh, the vice president would like you to leave the White House
離開白宮
before she's sworn in.
她認為最好不要傳出什么她就職時
She doesn't think it would be a good idea for word to get out
你還在白宮的消息
that you were here when it happened.
本人莊嚴宣誓  我必忠實執行
I do solemnly swear that I will faithfully execute
合眾國總統職務
the office of President of the United States,
忠于職守  竭盡全力  恪守  維護
and will to the best of my ability preserve, protect
和捍衛合眾國憲法
and defend the Constitution of the United States.
-愿上帝助我  -又是這熟悉的一幕
- So help me God. - Here we are again.
知道嗎  如果你忽略盛大的儀式和場合
You know, if you ignore all the pomp and circumstance,
最反常的事就是我真的相信總統之位
the most perverse thing is I actually believe in the presidency.
其重要性
Its importance.
對世界的重大意義  哪怕只是象征性的
What it means around the world, even symbolically.
但我更相信權力  信它本身
But I believe in power even more. For its own sake.
戈爾·維達爾[作家]曾寫道
Gore Vidal once wrote
權力的目的是權力
that power is an end to itself,
而奪取勝利的本能沖動
and the instinctive urge to prevail...
是人類最為重要的特性
the most important single human trait.
我總是告訴我自己  我做的一切都是為了她
I've always told myself that everything I did was for her.
但也許并不是  也許我更愛權力
But maybe it wasn't. Maybe I love power more.
為你  和你親愛的人
For you, and for any dear to you,
我愿做任何事
I would do anything.
如果有幸  我的生涯中
If my career were of that better kind
有做出犧牲的機會或是能力
that there was any opportunity or capacity to sacrifice in it,
我愿抓住一切機會  為你和你親愛的人犧牲
I would embrace any sacrifice for you and for those dear to you.
在寧靜的時候  請記得我
Try to hold me in your mind, at some quiet times,
記得我這番熱情而真摯的話
as ardent and sincere in this one thing.
那一天終會到來
The time will come,
那一天已經不遠
the time will not be long in coming,
你將建立起新的關系
when new ties will be formed about you.
那關系將會更加溫情而有力地把你
The ties that will bind you yet more tenderly and strongly
跟你悉心經營的家連結在一起
to the home you so adorn.
那是永遠為你增光  令你幸福的最親密的關系
The dearest ties that will ever grace and gladden you.
馬內特小姐
Oh, Miss Manette,
等一個長得
when the little picture
和他幸福的父親一樣的小家伙仰起臉看你時
of a happy father's face looks up in yours...
晚上好
Good evening.
晚上好  女士們先生們  我叫肖恩·杰弗瑞斯
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. My name is Sean Jeffries.
我是新新聞部副主任
I'm the new deputy director of communications.
賽斯去哪了
Where's Seth?
格雷森先生上臺前被叫走了
Mr. Grayson got called away last minute,
所以我臨時替代一下他
so I'm temporarily filling his shoes.
我不回答問題
I won't be taking any questions.
我要讀一份擬好的聲明
Instead, I'll be reading from a prepared statement.
幾小時前
A few hours ago,
安德伍德總統
President Underwood resigned
辭去了美國總統一職
the office of President of the United States.
在有白宮人員參加的私密儀式上
And in a private ceremony attended by staff,
克萊爾·安德伍德總統宣誓就職
President Claire Underwood was sworn in.
即刻生效  她將擔任
Effective immediately, she will be assuming the office
美國總統一職
of President of the United States.
稍后會具體公布將由
Details will be coming shortly on who will
-誰來接任  -你一定很為他驕傲
- be stepping into the office as - You must be so proud of him.
副總統
vice president.
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德總統今天雖無法親自前來
And while President Francis Underwood couldn't be here today...
三小時前進行了權力交接
Transfer of power happened three hours ago,
過程"私密而低調"
quote, "privately and quietly."
頭版頭條就是它了
And that's above the fold.
-司法部有什么消息嗎  -還沒有
- Anything from DOJ? - Nothing yet.
馬克·厄舍沒有正式頭銜
No official title to him,
但權力交接是他主持的
but it's Mark Usher running the transition.
好  我們來看看誰進誰出
Okay. Let's find out who's in and who's out.
多米諾骨牌在不斷倒下
The dominoes are falling.
-誰負責調查羅梅洛  -我
- Now, who's on Romero? - Here.
-我們想讓議員公開發聲  -好的
- We want the congressman on the record. - I've got it.
留著麥卡倫周末再爆料
And let's save Macallan for the weekend.
湯姆  道格·斯坦普怎么樣了
Tom, where are we with Doug Stamper?
我得去核查點東西
There's, uh, something I need to check on.
頭條網  消息網
Slugline, BuzzFeed,
全市一半的新聞渠道都等著這則大新聞呢
half the outlets in this city are ready to jump on this.
你跟他一對一談過
You spoke to him. One on one.
-他沒說是他干的  -他不用說
- He didn't actually say he did it. - He doesn't have to.
有人知道賽斯·格雷森對聯邦檢察官說了什么嗎
Does anyone know what Seth Grayson said to the US attorney?
湯姆
Tom?
你寫這屆政府寫了兩年了
Two years you've been writing about this administration.
-機會來了  -我想繼續追查而已
- This is it. - I want to follow up, that's all.
我看見一座美麗的城市
I see a beautiful city
和一個燦爛的民族從這深淵中升起
and a brilliant people rising from this abyss.
在他們爭取真正的自由的奮斗中
And in their struggles to be truly free,
在他們的勝利與失敗中
in their triumphs and defeats,
在未來的漫長歲月中
through long years to come,
我看見這一時代的邪惡和前一時代的邪惡
I see the evil of this time and of the previous time
前者是后者的自然結果
of which this is the natural birth,
逐漸贖去自己的罪孽  慢慢消失
gradually making expiation for itself and wearing out.
華盛頓時間今天凌晨三點左右
Surface-to-surface missiles delivered sarin
地對地沙林毒氣導彈
at about three o'clock in the morning, our time.
莫斯科已經發出聲明  譴責反政府軍
Moscow has already issued a statement condemning the rebels
策劃了這場苦肉計襲擊
for orchestrating the attack on themselves.
-真是嗎  -當然不是
- And did they? - Of course not.
佩特羅夫是想利用它發動正當空襲
Petrov will use this to justify air strikes.
我給你看張照片
I'd like to show you an image.
這張是路透社的
This one is coming out of Reuters.
我有預感  上午大多數媒體都會發這張
The feeling is most of the press will be using it by the a.m.
依我的經驗
Experience tells me
這件事會回響個三五天
this will resonate for about three to five days...
也就給了我們機會
which gives us our window.
我們可以準備一份聲明
Well, we can ready a statement.
出兵才是真正的聲明
Troops on the ground is the statement.
不  我想等找到艾哈邁迪再行動
No, I don't want to do anything until we find Ahmadi's location.
我不確定這件事我們應該選擇等待  總統女士
I'm not sure we should wait on this, Madam President.
我想提醒你發出最后通牒的
I'd like to remind you that it was this administration
正是這個政府
that introduced the ultimatum.
你該有所行動
You should act on it.
是  但我都沒有像樣的團隊
Yes, but I barely have a team in place.
你可以用前總統的團隊
Well, you can run it by the former president...
前總統就是前總統
The former president is just that.
機會就在眼前
An opportunity has presented itself.
而我想把握住機會
And I'm trying to take advantage of it.
-大家都在戰況室了嗎  -20分鐘前都齊了
- Is everyone in the Situation Room? - As of 20 minutes ago.
時機不對
So, the timing is bad.
如果現在赦免他  會顯得你跟他的罪行有關
If you pardon him now, you're associated with his crimes.
共和黨人會咬著你不放
Republicans will have a field day.
我們需要掩護
We need some cover.
那就是抓捕艾哈邁迪
Well, that would be Ahmadi's capture.
合適的副總統對我們有好處
The right VP would help all this.
你有更多想法嗎
Have you had any further thoughts?
最終名單沒變
My short list is the same.
韋斯特維爾特  克拉克  克萊因
Westervelt, Clark, Klein.
克萊因最有可能
Klein would be the strongest bulwark
抵抗對你的彈劾
against calls for your impeachment.
-這是剜肉補瘡  -補瘡是關鍵
- Swallowing poison to stay alive. - Alive is good.
我覺得我受不了克萊因
I don't think I can stomach Klein.
他稱我為賤人  不如克拉克
He called me a bitch. I prefer Clark.
告訴我  搬走尸體前
Tell me. Before you moved the body,
你幫他合上雙眼了嗎
were you able to close his eyes?
合上了
Yes.
我知道你很重視他的想法
Look... I know his opinion means a lot to you.
弗蘭西斯
Francis.
但讓他待在白宮  即便在東廂
But having him here, in the White House, even in the East Wing,
也會干擾我們處理事情
while we're trying to figure this out, it's hard.
總會有人暗示
At some point, someone is going to imply
仍是他在做決定
that he is still making the decisions.
那可不妙
That wouldn't be good.
-我會給她建議  她會想通的  -但愿吧
- I'll advise her. She'll come around. - I hope so.
敘利亞的事  如果她現在不行動
Because if she doesn't act now, when it comes to Syria,
她的總統位子就坐不穩
her presidency could be in danger.
你的未來也有變數
And your future in doubt.
別威脅我  戴維斯女士
Oh, don't threaten me, Ms. Davis.
我不威脅別人
I don't threaten.
我只是想盡量說清楚
I just try to remain as clear as possible.
你幫我做事  我也幫你做事
You offered me your services, and I offered you mine.
要知道
You know...
我比你早來  也會比你晚走
I was here before you and I'll be here after you.
即便如此  讓我提醒你
And regardless of that, let me remind you...
沒有比我更危險的東西
that nothing is more dangerous than me.
你現在得務實  戴維斯沒說錯
You need to be practical now. Davis isn't wrong.
我們已經想抓捕艾哈邁迪一年了  弗蘭西斯
We've been trying to get our hands on Ahmadi for a year, Francis.
-她還沒有實現  -沒錯  但關鍵不是她
- She hasn't delivered. - Yes, but this isn't about her.
而是你  還有第一次向全國發表講話
This is about you and coming out with a strong message
傳達出來的有力信息
in your first address to the nation.
關鍵是為你的任期定下基調
This is about setting the course for your presidency.
要強大  克萊爾
Be strong, Claire.
開戰吧
Go to war.
但我需要你離開
But I need you to leave.
離開白宮
Leave the White House.
是  我懂
Yes, I see.
為了能成功赦免你  弗蘭西斯
For this pardon to succeed, Francis,
我們得表現得有所疏遠
we need to appear to be estranged.
這只是策略
I'm just being strategic.
你建議我去哪
And where do you suggest I go?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
海軍天文臺
The Naval Observatory?
我覺得副總統府邸還是太近了
I think the vice president's residence is still too close.
抱歉  我只是...
I'm sorry, I just...
我們不能讓別人認為你還在干政
We can't have anyone think you're still involved in policy.
如果你動搖了
Look, if you're having second thoughts,
-你現在就該告訴我  -不
- you should tell me now. - No.
-我完全同意  -因為這可不是猶豫的時候
- No. I'm in full agreement. - 'Cause this is no time to hesitate.
我沒在猶豫
I am not hesitating.
我只是覺得如果我們不妥當處理
I just believe if we don't play this correctly,
那對公眾而言
as far as the public,
我的任期不過就是我倆茍且偷生
my term will be nothing but survival for both of us.
好吧
All right.
我希望你知道我會幫助你
I want you to know I'm here
如果你需要政策或其他事情的建議
if you need any advice on policy or anything else you might need.
謝謝你  我去睡了
Thank you. I'm going to bed.
沒有人會像我一樣愛你
No one will ever love you as much as I do.
我希望你知道
I hope you know that.
就像我知道沒有人會像你一樣愛我
Just as I know that no one will ever love me... like you.
"在陶瓷青蛙下面"
"Under the porcelain frog."
答案必須準確  包括大小寫
The answers are case-sensitive and exact.
只有一次機會
You won't get a second chance.
-第二個問題  -我最喜歡的棒球運動員嗎
- And the middle one? - My favorite baseball player?
"韋德·博格斯"  兩個G
"Wade Boggs." Two G's.
最后一個
And the last?
"你在奧斯丁的酒店房間留了什么"
"What did you leave in that hotel room in Austin?"
我的槍在哪
Where is my gun?
給
Here you go.
你能給我什么保證
What guarantees do I have?
我把槍還給你了
I gave you your gun back.
但你為什么給他  我很好奇
But what made you give it to him? I'm curious.
我覺得他有危險
I thought he was in danger.
那你現在怎么覺得
And now you think what?
我想問的就是這個
That is what I'm asking.
只要我在  你會一直是本屆政府的成員
As long as I'm around, you'll be a part of this administration.
我們都知道艾丹太多事
We both know too much about Aidan.
克萊爾知道你有多忠誠  我很確定
And Claire knows how loyal you are. I'm sure of it.
所以  你在奧斯丁的酒店房間留了什么
So, what did you leave in that hotel room in Austin?
一條手鏈
A bracelet.
真糟糕
That's too bad.
我終于看到了
You know, I finally got a look
麥卡倫留給哈維小姐的東西
at what Macallan passed on to Ms. Harvey.
你和你丈夫偷走了這場大選
I was shocked to realize the degree
程度之深  真是讓我震驚了
to which you and your husband stole this election.
我得對你實話實說
I need to be honest with you.
我和他談過
I've been in talks with him about
幫他發起一個基金會
helping him start a foundation of some kind.
換取對你的影響
In exchange for influence over you.
有意思
Interesting.
我想幫你度過這個過渡期
I'm trying to help you navigate this transition.
你對于我是什么人
Who are you to me?
你希望我是什么人
Who do you want me to be?
這個回答不好
That's not a good answer.
你是美國第一任女總統
You're the first woman President of the United States.
你忍了那么多  做了那么多犧牲和妥協
All you've had to swallow, the sacrifices, the compromises.
你會想要自我隔離
You're gonna want to isolate yourself.
不去相信任何人
Not trust anyone.
但你需要的正是這個
But that's exactly what you're gonna need.
需要有人告訴你真相
Someone to tell you what's what.
你就是這個人嗎
And is that person you?
是嗎
Is it?
我覺得不論我說什么都沒法讓你相信
I don't think there's anything i could say that would convince you
除非你已經感覺到了
if you don't already feel it.
戴維斯女士  你在要求我發動戰爭
Ms. Davis, you are asking me to start a war.
而你似乎只在你樂意時兌現諾言
And you seem to deliver on promises when it suits you.
所以  原諒我懷疑你的意圖
So forgive me if I question your intentions.
我喜歡你
I like you.
我喜歡在你身邊
I like being around you.
有時這讓我失去了應有的效率
And sometimes that makes me less effective than I should be.
不論是否赦免你丈夫
Pardoning or not pardoning your husband,
他都是個不利因素
in either case, he's a liability.
如果治療不當
If it's not treated properly...
你丈夫的肝臟隨時可能衰竭
your husband's liver could fail him at any time.
這種事我做不了
It's not the kind of thing I could do.
但我可以找人  或者...
But I could find someone, or...
我...不知你是否知道
I... I don't know if you realize,
即便是胡蔓藤這種藥物
but... even something like gelsemium
劑量太高時  也可能致命
can be lethal in higher doses.
我丈夫的健康狀況沒問題
My husband's health is just fine.
我會繼續和他合作  跟隨你的領導
I'll continue to work with him. Follow your lead.
這是我委托人的護照
Here's my client's passport.
有幾件事我們要再重申一下
There's a few things we want to go over.
還沒重申過的嗎
That we haven't already?
我必須確定  你們帶他出去時不戴手銬
No cuffs, when you walk him out of here. I need to be sure.
拜托  詹姆斯  我們不會這么干的
Oh, come on, James, we aren't gonna play that on this.
你有些很夠意思的朋友  斯坦普先生
You have some very good friends, Mr. Stamper,
沒讓媒體報道這件事
to keep the press out of this.
你會像個紳士一樣走出去
You will walk out of here like a gentleman.
我們要他12小時內面見法官
We want him in front of the judge within 12 hours.
我們還不知道是否會起訴他
We don't even know if we're gonna charge him yet.
是我做的
I did it.
繼續吧
Let's get going.
你在她的內閣里有什么人
Who do you have on her cabinet?
現在還只是建議
Right now, they're just suggestions.
拜托  我們都知道這是怎么回事
Oh, come on. We both know how this works.
你已經做了決定
You've already made your choices.
如果沒有  那就是你沒本事
You wouldn't be worth your salt if you hadn't.
我只是希望你先讓我過目一下
I just want you to run them by me first.
我能讓這個過渡很輕松  也能給你制造麻煩
Look, I can make this transition easy for you or not.
給你一句忠告
And a word of advice.
她會需要
She's gonna need some
桌子那邊坐著一些友好的面孔
friendly faces looking at her across that table.
會有一些人...
There'll be a few...
按要求微笑的
who will smile as required.
你看看這個
Would you look at this?
都是前特種部隊的
Both Special Forces. Former.
他們知道如何忘記  所以你不必擔心
They know how to forget, so you don't have to worry about them.
尸體呢
And the body?
處理好了
It's on ice.
我剛剛和納澤取得了聯系
I just made contact with Nasser.
我們已經拿到了艾哈邁迪的位置
We have secured the location of Ahmadi.
我來召集隊伍
I'll assemble the team.
我已經給戴爾海軍上將打過電話了
I called Admiral Dale already.
那我們現在得做些決定
So we have some decisions to make.
一旦我們派部隊過去
Once we have troops on the ground,
我們需要仔細看一下
we'll need to take a close look
我們為你的內閣考慮的人選
at who we're considering for your cabinet.
你身邊需要有戰時經驗的團隊
You'll need a team around you with wartime experience.
我有些建議  已經傳達給馬克了
I have some suggestions I've passed on to Mark.
我認為中情局的副局長  瑪茜·西格森
I think Deputy Director of the CIA, Marcy Siegerson,
會是極佳的國務卿人選
would make a terrific Secretary of State.
我很容易與其協調聯系
Someone I could easily liaison with.
我還希望
Well, I was hoping that
你會以某種形式加入我的內閣
you would be on my cabinet, in some capacity.
我會在圈外工作
I'll be operating out of the region.
那是我的強項
It's where my strength lies.
我們有更好的能夠接手的人選
There are better people who can take it from here,
能夠在大后方給你建議
advise you on the home front.
哈維小姐  莉安  我們需要調動一下你的職位
And Ms. Harvey, LeAnn, we need to move you.
當然只是暫時的
Uh, just for now, of course.
我以為...
It was my understanding that...
現在一個更老道的幕僚長
Right now a more seasoned Chief of Staff
會向國會和國家傳遞
would send a strong message
強有力的信息  目前是這樣
to the Congress and to the nation. For now.
她會做的  她會派部隊過去
She'll do it. She'll send in the troops.
明天下午我就會到迪拜了
I'll be in Dubai by tomorrow afternoon.
我們的交易依舊不變
And our deal stays in place.
等一下
Yeah, hold on a second.
-準備好了嗎  -好了
- Ready?  - Go ahead.
是的  哈維女士拿回了她的槍
Yes. Ms. Harvey has her gun back.
麥卡倫的檔案在總統那里
Macallan's files are with the president.
任何能把你和選舉聯系起來的有力證據...
Any hard evidence connecting you to the election...
都在她手上
is in her hands.
那么莉安的工作結束了
Then LeAnn's job is done.
如果你還有什么要說的  現在是時候了
If you have anything to say, now is the time.
你覺得發生了什么
What do you think happened?
我更希望你來告訴我
I'd prefer you tell me that.
遷就我吧  是你要求見面的
Humor me. You asked for this meeting.
你覺得發生了什么
What do you think happened?
我相信佐伊·巴恩斯當時在調查
I believe Zoe Barnes was investigating
你和瑞秋·波斯納的關系
a relationship you were having with Rachel Posner.
不知怎么的  那會危及到
And somehow, that knowledge would endanger
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
Francis Underwood,
那個你會為其赴湯蹈火的人
who you would do anything for.
但是有人想過佐伊·巴恩斯的生命嗎
But did anyone think about the life of Zoe Barnes?
你覺得你能抹去一些東西
You know, you think you can erase something.
然后你發現那是不可能的
Then you find out that's not possible.
湯姆  我的律師根本不想讓我和你交談
Tom, my attorneys didn't even want me to speak with you.
抱歉  沒什么好說的了
I'm sorry, there's just nothing more to say here.
我不知道瑞秋·波斯納怎么了
I don't know what happened to Rachel Posner.
但是我不相信是你殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
But I don't believe you killed Zoe Barnes.
錄像里的是你嗎
Is this you in this video?
看起來像是我
Looks like me.
我仔細思考了很久  弗蘭西斯
I've thought long and hard, Francis.
幾乎沒睡
Barely slept.
這份工作就是這樣
That's the job.
我準備派部隊過去
I'm going to send in troops.
我明晚就會宣布
I'll be announcing it tomorrow night.
我覺得你做了正確的事
I think you're doing the right thing.
你討厭這兒嗎
Do you hate it here?
你知道的  我不喜歡賓館
Oh, you know I don't like hotels.
看著像家  但只是提醒你并不在家
An approximation of home just to remind you you're not there.
我們不是有家的人
Well, we don't live in a home.
我們有一座白宮  借來暫住
We live in a house, borrowed and temporary.
你的眼睛里有什么  有種眼神
Something in your eye. A look.
不一樣了
It's changed.
你和我  現在是一樣的了
We're the same now, you and I.
-怎么說  -你明白的
- How so? - You know how.
我很久沒讓我自己感到驚奇了
It's been a long time since I surprised myself.
你會恢復的
You'll recover.
你是世界上權力最大的女人  克萊爾
You're the most powerful woman in the world, Claire.
任何慰藉都難與匹敵
Comfort pales by comparison.
我會在宣布出兵之后宣布這條消息
I'll announce it during the speech, after the troops.
將全面無條件地赦免
A full and unconditional pardon...
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德在擔任美國總統期間
for Francis Underwood and any crimes he might have committed
可能犯下的任何罪行
against the United States while president.
我很高興知道這一點
I'm glad to hear that.
我從沒動搖過  我只是需要考慮一下方式
It was never in doubt. I just needed to think about how.
那這個安排要維持多久
So how long does this arrangement last?
暫時先這樣吧
For the time being.
我們是怎么到這一步的  弗蘭西斯
How did we get here, Francis?
別糾結了  已經過去了
Oh, let it go. It's done.
對了  再給你個建議
Oh, and one word of advice.
不管厄舍向你推薦誰做副總統
Whomever Usher offers up to you as vice president,
這個人就是你真正應該小心的人
that's the person that you're really gonna have to watch.
我應付不了的人  我是不會選的
I won't choose anyone I can't manage.
在樓的西南角  繼續觀察
Southwest corner of the building. Maintain visual.
收到
Copy that.
扔雷
Frag out!
艾哈邁迪在那兒  我看到艾哈邁迪了
There's Ahmadi. I have visual on Ahmadi.
-我看到他了  -沖  開火
- I see him. - Go, go! Fire!
我犯了個大錯
I made a terrible mistake.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我都不知道我在做什么  我
I don't even know what I'm doing here. I, uh...
早上我開著車就出來了  我怕了
This morning I started driving. I... I got scared.
總之我正往回趕  我能去見你嗎
Anyway, I'm on my way back. Can I come see you?
當然
Yes, please.
有時候看電影  你并不一定要看到最后
Sometimes you don't have to watch the whole movie
才知道結局
to know how it ends.
兩黨對演講的反應應該會都不錯
The speech is gonna play well with both parties.
和共和黨人談得怎么樣了
Where are we with the Republicans?
關于你的內閣  我們正在交換名單
Trading names when it comes to your cabinet.
選了幾個將軍  這會有利
We have our generals, which is good.
有幾個是公司出身  圈外人
Some corporate types, outsiders.
讓你看著像個打破陳規的人
Make you seem like a renegade.
公司  從哪來的
Corporate, from where?
大多數是石油和銀行業  也有搞技術的
Oil, banking, mostly. Some tech.
再摻幾個特區的長期議員
Occasional D.C. lifer sprinkled into the mix
好讓你的內閣按時開工
to make sure the trains run on time.
我在看副總統的名單
I was going over our list for vice president.
等等
Yeah. Hold on.
這可能有點意外
this will seem unexpected,
但是我問過的許多人都說我最合適
but a lot of the people I spoke to suggested me.
可你不是政客
You're not a politician.
沒錯
Exactly.
但我可以守在你身邊
But I could be by your side.
這樣國會兩院大多數人都傷不到我們
Most of the Hill and the Senate would not come near us.
我會考慮的
I'll take it into consideration.
不能考慮了  你需要我
It's beyond that. You'll need me.
什么
Excuse me?
我能幫你
I can help. Look...
只有這樣才能保住你的位子
It is the way to keep you in power.
和你的秘密
And keep your secrets.
晚上好
Good evening.
我在此向全體美國人民和全世界鄭重宣布
I'm here to report to the American people and the world
在今天上午
that early this morning,
特種部隊擊斃了哈里發國恐怖分子
Special Forces killed the ICO terrorist
艾哈邁德·艾哈邁迪
Ahmed Al Ahmadi.
我們干掉他了
We got him.
我們消滅他了
在每一位男女總統任職期間
Now, there comes a time in every president's tenure
他們總會面臨這么一個問題  就是要不要
when he or she must face the question of whether or not
派遣美國年輕人上陣殺敵
to send young American soldiers into harm's way.
對我而言
In my case...
我上任之初  就要面對這個難題了
that time has fallen within the very first days of my presidency.
俄羅斯總統維克多·佩特羅夫與中國合謀
Russian President Viktor Petrov collaborated with the Chinese
試圖在南極洲非法開采石油
on illegal oil exploration in Antarctica.
最近我們又了解到  他已派出軍隊
Recently, we have learned that he has sent troops
與敘利亞當局并肩作戰
to fight alongside the Syrian regime,
協助他們毀滅敘利亞國家
assisting them in the destruction of the Syrian nation.
政府軍使用化學武器攻擊自己的人民
These forces are using chemical weapons on their own people,
折磨異議人士
torturing the opposition,
讓全國絕大多數人口忍饑挨餓
and starving huge segments of the population.
敘利亞人民已飽受戰亂之苦
The Syrians are a people besieged.
不要再讓他們被遺忘了
Let them not also be forgotten.
我們將怒火轉化成行動的時機已經到來
The time has come for our outrage to be turned into action.
五個月前  我丈夫
Five months ago, my husband
曾向眾議院發出呼吁
addressed the House of Representatives
要求他們向哈里發國宣戰
and asked them to declare war on ICO.
國會讓他失望了
Congress failed him.
國會讓人民失望了
Congress failed you.
哈里發國極端分子圖謀讓我們的民主和國家
ICO extremists want democracy and America itself
轟然崩塌
to die a fiery death.
我們決不能讓他們得逞
We cannot allow that to happen.
我們不能再等待國會了
We can't wait for Congress any longer.
我們給國會的機會已經夠多了
We gave Congress every chance.
她是不打算說了
She isn't going to say it.
歷史在評判每一位領袖  每一位總統的時候
Now, history judges every leader, every president,
都要看他或她是怎么對待自己的人民的
by how he or she treats his or her own people.
一個悍然攻擊醫院  難民營
A regime that would target hospitals, refugee camps,
學校和救濟車隊
schools or bread lines
只為了自保的政權  必須受到懲罰
in order to retain power must be confronted.
而身為國家領袖  卻犧牲
A leader that would sacrifice
自己人民的幸福安康
the physical and emotional well-being of his citizens,
視人民如棋子籌碼
that would treat his people as pawns,
就為了保住自己的權力
just to stay in power? Well...
這樣的領袖必須下臺
that leader needs to be stopped.
如果她不赦免我
If she doesn't pardon me...
我就殺了她
I'll kill her.
謝謝你們  上帝保佑我們偉大的國家
Thank you and God bless this great country.
電話已經涌進來了
Well, the calls are coming in already.
講得好  今晚對你非常有利
Well done. This'll be a good night for you.
莫斯科那邊還沒有動靜
Nothing from Moscow yet.
現在我想自己待一會兒
Right now I just need some time to myself.
你認識湯姆·耶茨嗎
Do you know Tom Yates?
不熟  怎么了
Not personally. Why?
他有段時間沒出現了
He hasn't been around in a while.
沒事  算了
I don't know, forget it.
怎么了
What?
我一直在聯系他  而他通常都回電話的
I've been calling him. And he usually answers.
我們要正義  我們要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中東不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我們要正義  我們要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中東不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我們要正義  我們要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中東不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我們要正義  我們要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace...
白宮外爆發的反戰示威游行
The anti- war demonstrations outside the White House
終于出了狀況
finally got out of hand.
這里是莉安·哈維  請留言
You've reached LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
一名抗議者翻過圍欄
One of the protesters made his way over the gates.
在穿越白宮草坪的時候
As he was running across the White House lawn,
被趕來的特勤局特工包圍
Secret Service agents moved in,
該名抗議者不幸被擊斃
tragically shooting and killing the man.
這里是莉安·哈維  請留言
You've reached LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
你在哪呢
Hey, where are you?
抱歉  女士  今晚是不行了
I'm sorry, ma'am, it's just not possible tonight.
我們無法確保跑步路線安全
We can't secure the run.
目前威脅等級太高了
The level of threat at this point is just too high.
-好的  謝謝你  -好的  女士
- Okay. Thank you. - Yes, ma'am.
該我了
My turn.
在過去幾年中  美國對敘利亞的政策一直是外交事務的中心
而奧巴馬和特朗普兩任總統在這一事務中采取了截然不同的立場
2012年8月20日  奧巴馬宣布"阿薩德政權如果使用化武便越過了'紅線'"
2013年8月21日  媒體報道敘利亞境內大量平民遭到化武襲擊
1429人罹難  包括426名兒童
全世界都以為奧巴馬將對敘動武  美軍軍艦也部署完畢
但奧巴馬臨時改了主意  決定暫停武裝打擊計劃  而尋求國會授權
最終不了了之  許多評論認為  此后普京在東歐放手東擴
也是覺得奧巴馬外交上比較軟弱  不會干涉克里姆林宮的行為
特朗普上任后  也遇到了阿薩德使用化武的事件
由于競選時他反對過度干預國際事務  所以白宮雖發表了嚴厲聲明
但媒體和美國公眾  都沒預料到特朗普真的會有決心進行武力打擊
4月6日晚  白宮和五角大樓向媒體宣布
特朗普下令讓部署在地中海的兩艘美國海軍軍艦
向敘利亞政府軍的一個空軍基地  發射了60枚戰斧導彈
摧毀了該基地的一些設施和戰斗機
特朗普上任后  屢屢受到批評  媒體也多次爆出他的丑聞
但敘利亞打擊后  不僅參眾兩院的民主黨領袖都公開發表聲明
對此舉表示肯定和認可  媒體也破天荒地交口稱贊
打擊敘利亞成了特朗普總統生涯中  迄今為止最閃光的時刻